<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Part1s on Intent-Oriented Software Engineering</title><link>/en/part1/</link><description>Recent content in Part1s on Intent-Oriented Software Engineering</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="/en/part1/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Chapter 1: What is Intent-Oriented Software Engineering</title><link>/en/part1/01-what-is-iose/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/en/part1/01-what-is-iose/</guid><description>&lt;h1&gt;
 Chapter 1: What is Intent-Oriented Software Engineering
 &lt;/h1&gt;





 &lt;h2 id="1-a-core-proposition"&gt;
 1 A Core Proposition
 &lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Software engineering is undergoing a profound paradigm shift, where future software development will no longer be a craft centered around code, but a new engineering form—&lt;strong&gt;Intent-Oriented Software Engineering (IOSE)&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The essence of &amp;ldquo;intent-oriented&amp;rdquo; lies in introducing large model agents (Agents) into the core of software production, allowing them to replace human programmers, testers, and even architects in undertaking repetitive implementation work in traditional development processes—from writing detailed design documents to writing specific code, constructing test cases, building automation scripts, and executing unit tests. Under this paradigm, as long as humans can express intent accurately and completely, large models can efficiently transform it into runnable software systems.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Chapter 2: Why This Transformation is Needed</title><link>/en/part1/02-why-iose/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/en/part1/02-why-iose/</guid><description>&lt;h1&gt;
 Chapter 2: Why This Transformation is Needed
 &lt;/h1&gt;





 &lt;h2 id="1-the-fundamental-contradiction-of-software-engineering"&gt;
 1 The Fundamental Contradiction of Software Engineering
 &lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking back at the more than half-century development of software engineering, this field has always been troubled by a fundamental contradiction: &lt;strong&gt;the structural conflict between rapidly changing business requirements and the high cost of modifying software systems.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To understand the essence of this contradiction, we must first analyze &lt;strong&gt;the dual sources of software complexity&lt;/strong&gt;. In the past, the essence of software complexity lay in the superposition of &lt;strong&gt;business complexity and technical complexity&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Chapter 3: Intent Layering</title><link>/en/part1/03-intent-layers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/en/part1/03-intent-layers/</guid><description>&lt;h1&gt;
 Chapter 3: Intent Layering
 &lt;/h1&gt;





 &lt;h2 id="1-why-layering-is-needed"&gt;
 1 Why Layering is Needed
 &lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Intent is never a single-dimensional simple instruction, but a layered semantic system. Let us understand this through a concrete scenario: when an executive says &amp;ldquo;we want to develop a membership system&amp;rdquo; at a project kickoff meeting, different roles in the room actually receive completely different information—&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The CEO&lt;/strong&gt; envisions numbers on financial statements: can this system improve user retention? Can it bring considerable revenue growth? How does it support the company&amp;rsquo;s long-term competitive moat?&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>